<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<androidx.constraintlayout.widget.ConstraintLayout xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android"
    xmlns:app="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto"
    xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
    android:id="@+id/main"
    android:layout_width="match_parent"
    android:layout_height="match_parent"
    android:background="#F5F5F5"
    tools:context=".History">

    <!-- ðŸ“± Top Bar Container -->
    <LinearLayout
        android:id="@+id/topBar"
        android:layout_width="match_parent"
        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
        android:orientation="horizontal"
        android:gravity="center_vertical"
        android:paddingStart="12dp"
        android:paddingEnd="20dp"
        android:paddingTop="16dp"
        android:paddingBottom="16dp"
        android:elevation="2dp"
        android:background="@color/white"
        app:layout_constraintTop_toTopOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintStart_toStartOf="parent"
        app:layout_constraintEnd_toEndOf="parent">

        <!-- ðŸ”™ Back Button -->
        <ImageButton
            android:id="@+id/backButton"
            android:layout_width="40dp"
            android:layout_height="40dp"
            android:background="?attr/selectableItemBackgroundBorderless"
            android:src="@drawable/back_icon"
            android:contentDescription="Back"
            android:padding="8dp"
            app:tint="@android:color/black" />

        <!-- ðŸ« Title -->
        <TextView
            android:id="@+id/titleText"
            android:layout_width="0dp"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:layout_weight="1"
            android:text="History of BulSU - Bustos Campus"
            android:textSize="16sp"
            android:textColor="@android:color/black"
            android:fontFamily="sans-serif-medium"
            android:gravity="center"
            android:paddingStart="8dp"
            android:paddingEnd="8dp"
            android:maxLines="2"
            android:ellipsize="end" />

        <!-- Spacer to balance the title -->
        <Space
            android:layout_width="40dp"
            android:layout_height="40dp" />
    </LinearLayout>

    <!-- ðŸ“œ Scrollable Content -->
    <androidx.core.widget.NestedScrollView
        android:id="@+id/scrollView"
        android:layout_width="match_parent"
        android:layout_height="0dp"
        android:fillViewport="true"
        android:scrollbars="none"
        app:layout_constraintTop_toBottomOf="@id/topBar"
        app:layout_constraintBottom_toBottomOf="parent">

        <LinearLayout
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:orientation="vertical"
            android:paddingBottom="32dp">

            <!-- ðŸ–¼ Image Container -->
            <androidx.cardview.widget.CardView
                android:layout_width="match_parent"
                android:layout_height="wrap_content"
                android:layout_marginStart="20dp"
                android:layout_marginEnd="20dp"
                android:layout_marginTop="20dp"
                app:cardCornerRadius="16dp"
                app:cardElevation="6dp">

                <ImageView
                    android:id="@+id/historyImage"
                    android:layout_width="match_parent"
                    android:layout_height="240dp"
                    android:src="@drawable/bulsu_bustos"
                    android:scaleType="centerCrop"
                    android:contentDescription="BulSU Bustos Campus" />
            </androidx.cardview.widget.CardView>

            <!-- ðŸ“ Content Card -->
            <androidx.cardview.widget.CardView
                android:layout_width="match_parent"
                android:layout_height="wrap_content"
                android:layout_marginStart="20dp"
                android:layout_marginEnd="20dp"
                android:layout_marginTop="20dp"
                app:cardCornerRadius="16dp"
                app:cardElevation="4dp"
                android:backgroundTint="@color/white">

                <LinearLayout
                    android:layout_width="match_parent"
                    android:layout_height="wrap_content"
                    android:orientation="vertical"
                    android:padding="24dp">

                    <!-- ðŸ“š Section Title -->
                    <TextView
                        android:id="@+id/sectionTitle"
                        android:layout_width="match_parent"
                        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
                        android:text="Our History"
                        android:textSize="24sp"
                        android:textColor="#1A1A1A"
                        android:fontFamily="sans-serif-medium"
                        android:letterSpacing="0.01"
                        android:layout_marginBottom="8dp" />

                    <!-- Decorative divider -->
                    <View
                        android:layout_width="60dp"
                        android:layout_height="3dp"
                        android:background="#004600"
                        android:layout_marginBottom="20dp" />

                    <!-- ðŸ§¾ History Text with better formatting -->
                    <TextView
                        android:id="@+id/historyText"
                        android:layout_width="match_parent"
                        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
                        android:textColor="#2C2C2C"
                        android:textSize="15sp"
                        android:lineSpacingExtra="6dp"
                        android:fontFamily="serif"
                        android:justificationMode="inter_word"
                        android:letterSpacing="0.01"
                        android:text="The Bulacan State University Bustos Campus is the oldest and the first satellite campus of the university. It was initially organized when civic-minded citizens headed by the late General Alejo Santos established the Bustos Vocational and Technical School in November 1975.\n\nIt began to operate as an obscure non-formal training school, offering short term courses, temporarily housed at Bustos Central School. After six months of existence it was transferred to the present site and address at Poblacion, Bustos, Bulacan. The Voc-Tech school including its land, buildings and equipment was donated to the BULSU by the municipality of Bustos, Bulacan on May 12, 1976 by virtue of BCAT Board Resolution Number 400.\n\nIn the same year, Mr. Simplicio Reyes started managing the school as it offered secondary education and short-term courses like engine repair, tune-up, tailoring, practical electricity and drafting.\n\nIn 1977, Mr. Venancio Magdirila became in-charge of the Bustos Branch and was responsible in the expansion of program offerings to include secondary education. It was in his term in which initial plans to offer teacher educations were conceived but were not made into reality because of the acute shortage of facilities and faculty.\n\nIn June 1979, Mr. Aurelio F. Dionisio was designated In-Charge of the BCAT Bustos. Through his able leadership, Bustos Campus was able to pursue wide ranging physical plan development and added additional courses to the technical education offerings. The campus served as the hub for trade and industrial training in Bustos and its neighboring municipalities, which included the nearby towns of the province of Pampanga.\n\nMr Edgardo S. Mateo took over and continued the supervision of the campus even if the secondary education was being phased down/out due to the DECS/DBM resolutions of phasing out of secondary education in SUCs and transferring the secondary education to the DECS fold.\n\nIn 1992, Dr. Danilo S. Hilario was designated as director of the Bustos Branch and of the Auxiliary Service of the College with the Secondary Education completely phased out. He launched innovative plans of reengineering the goals and objectives of the campus.\n\nOne of his major accomplishments was the launching of an innovative plan to build up efficient citizen workers with inclusion of opportunity on terminal courses in Automotive Technology, Radio Mechanics, Cosmetology, Garments Trade, Drafting and Food Technology. Massive faculty development programs were launched that included in-service training to expose the faculty to the realm of college setting.\n\nIn 1993, Mr. Edgardo Mateo reassumed the directorship. In the preparation of offering teacher education and basic engineering, he embarked on physical development project. Under his term, the college building was constructed at the newly acquired 1.2 hectare lot at the back of the present location. He did not finish his term because of his sudden death.\n\nDr. Isabelita Santiago took over the directorship of the BSU Bustos Campus amidst back drop of expanding curricular programs and subsequent increase of enrollment not only in Bulacan but also from Northern and neighboring part and nearby towns of Pampanga. She pursued with vigor the development of BSU Bustos Campus by providing direction on the program offerings and ventured into faculty development programs provided by the administration, until her untimely death on May 21, 2002.\n\nIn June 2002, Professor Angelina D. Cinco was promoted from admission Coordinator to Acting Director. It was in August of the same year that she assumed the full Directorship of the campus. Additional majors in teacher education were envisioned to make its program more responsive to the changing needs of the new millennium. A food-processing center is also a part of her vision, which will open up the door of the university to its neighboring town and industry. And lastly, she also envisioned a review center for teacher education to help the graduates in the preparation for their licensure examination.\n\nDr. Ladislao D. Marcelo replaced Prof. Angelina D. Cinco who was transferred to the main campus to share her expertise in managing the BulSU-Hostel. Dr. Marcelo brought with him his vast experience as an AACCUP Accreditor and because of this he successfully led the campus to pass the AACCUP Level 1 Accreditation in March of 2007. Nonetheless, his stint in the Bustos Campus was cut short due to his transfer to the BulSU-Meneses Campus.\n\nIn October of 2007, Prof. Cornelio O. Garcia was appointed the new Director of the BulSU-Bustos Campus. The Guidance Counsellor cum English Professor, who has been connected from the Campus for the last 26 years, boasts of a remarkable record of managerial and counselling skills. He envisioned ushering in a new wave of paradigm shifts in the university branch and among the faculty members that paved the way to make the Campus break new grounds and reach greater heights.\n\nOn April 19, 2010, Dr. Alberto J. Valenzuela was designated as Director of Bustos Campus. Prior to his appointment as the new campus administrator, he was the Director of Public Employment Service Office (PESO) and has been assigned as one of the coordinators of in-plant training in the BulSU CIT, main campus. For two consecutive terms, he managed the affairs and operations of the Mechanical and Welding Technology Department of the CIT as area chairman.\n\nHis vast experiences as a member of the BulSU Board of Regents and as President of the Faculty Union for eight years helped him a lot to develop his leadership persona which he believes can be his most potent weapon in facing and addressing the intricacies of managing an academic institution. As a result of Dr. Valenzuela's competent administration, the Bulacan State University Bustos Campus had successfully passed the Level II Accreditation for the programs Bachelor of Secondary Education (BSED) Major in Physical Science and Bachelor in Industrial Technology (BIT) Majors in Automotive, Foods, Drafting, Electronics and Electrical. The Survey Visit was conducted by the Accredited Agencies of Chartered Colleges and Universities of the Philippines, INC. (AACCUP) on July 1, 2014.\n\nOn August 1, 2017, Dr. Ciriaco M. Garcia was designated the new Dean of the Campus. His strong determination and passion to lead make the Bulacan State University-Bustos Campus to soar higher and endeavor greater privileges."
                        tools:text="This is where the history text will appear." />
                </LinearLayout>
            </androidx.cardview.widget.CardView>
        </LinearLayout>
    </androidx.core.widget.NestedScrollView>

</androidx.constraintlayout.widget.ConstraintLayout>